Guide to the Alvin T. Parnell photographs of Durham, North Carolina, circa 1898-1986, bulk 1910-1960 RL.11373
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographs, circa 1898-1950s; 1; 85 items
  - People, circa 1898-1940s; 4; 25 items
    - Portrait of Mrs. E. Griffin, early 1940s? (Box 1, Image RL-11373-P-0074)
    - Portrait of Victor Bryant, 1930s? (Box 1, Image RL-11373-P-0075)
      Probably Victor Bryant Jr., prominent attorney and son of Durham lawyer and city attorney Victor Bryant.
    - Portrait of Durham Police Chief H. E. King, circa 1940 (Box 1, Image RL-11373-P-0076)
    - Portrait of unidentified bride, 1920s (Box 1, Image RL-11373-P-0077)
    - World War I veterans of the American Legion at a ceremony at Convention Center, Raleigh, N.C. (Box 1, Image RL-11373-P-0078)
      Caption from back of print.
    - Six unidentified women posed around a buffet table with punch bowl, 1940s? (Box 1, Image RL-11373-P-0079)
    - Young man and woman at elaborate trade show booth for American Tobacco Company, 1925 February 28 (Box 1, Image RL-11373-P-0080)
      Paper slip found with contact print reads: "2-28-25 / Durham Morning Herald's movie. / Durham's Hero? / Stills for Mr. Newland." Notes were taken by library staff from original negative sleeves.
    - Still from unidentified movie or tv set featuring a Mexican-style "cantina," with four unidentified actors performing a scene, early 1940s? (Box 1, Image RL-11373-P-0081)
      Two large cameras are visible on left and right frame edges; they appear to be television cameras. The actors are three men (one may be Latino), two in Mexican-style dress, and one woman of color also in Mexican-style dress.
    - Large dinner gathering (approx. 800 people), unknown location, 1940s (Box 2, Image RL-11373-P-0085)
      British flag along with U.S. flag may indicate a World War II-related event. 9 x 14 inches.
  - Other Images, 1920s; 5; 2 items
    Two images of a large and elaborate secretary desk by Wooton Desk Manufacturing Company.
    - Carved cabinet secretary or postal desk, by Wooton Desk Manufacturing Company, swinging doors open, circa 1920s (Box 1, Image RL-11373-P-0082)
      Wooton Desk Manufacturing, based in Indianapolis, went out of business around 1884. Printed on heavy fabric-backed photographic paper.
    - Carved cabinet secretary or postal desk, by Wooton Desk Manufacturing Company, swinging doors closed, circa 1920s (Box 1, Image RL-11373-P-0083)
- Contact Prints, circa 1910-1961; 82 items
  Sometime in the 1980s, library staff had 82 small contact prints printed from Parnell's nitrate negatives, which were then discarded. Many are duplicates of larger prints in the photographs series, but there are also images not found elsewhere in the collection. Captions and dates accompany about half of them, copied from their original sleeves. Arranged in numerical order applied by library staff.
  - Prints 1-20, 20 items (Box 1)
  - Prints 21-40, 20 items (Box 1)
  - Prints 41-60, 20 items (Box 1)
  - Prints 61-82, 22 items (Box 1)
- Negatives, circa 1902-1950s; 3; 12 items
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original negative are closed to general use; access only by permission of Rubenstein staff. Some copy prints are available. Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use these materials.
  Safety negatives on sheet film in 8x10 and 4x5 inch sizes. Some have prints already in collection; some are without accompanying prints. These are noted in the item listings.
  - Amoco gas station on unidentified wide city street, early 1950s (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0001)
    No print in collection.
  - Walker's Esso and a Texaco gas station, Holloway and Miami, looking east, early 1950s (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0002)
  - Walker's Esso gas station, looking west down Holloway St., early 1950s (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0003)
    No print in collection. One of two copies.
  - Walker's Esso gas station, looking west down Holloway St., early 1950s (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0004)
    No print in collection. Copy of previous negative 0003, same frame.
  - Walker's Esso and a Texaco gas stations, Holloway, looking east, with Moose Lodge in right foreground, early 1950s (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0005)
    Also visible is advertising billboard for Kenan Oil Company. No print in collection.
  - Walker's Esso gas station, another view, looking west down Holloway St., early 1950s (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0006)
  - Ellis, Stone & Co. dry goods store, horse-drawn wagon with two women in driver's seat and store window in background (Main St.?), circa 1905 (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0007)
    The store was located at 109 W. Main St. No print in collection.
  - Washington Duke and sons with associates at barbecue in Erwin, N.C. (then known as Duke), group portrait, circa 1902-1904 (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0008)
    From print also in Duke University Archives: front row, L to R: B.N. Duke, Washington Duke, J.B. Duke, T.J. Walker, A.B. Carrington, J.S. Cobb, and John Angier. Back row, L to R: Dr. A.G. Carr, W.A. Erwin, J. E. Stagg, Frank Tate, E.S. Yarbrough, Captain Lemon, and F.L. Fuller. No print in collection.
  - John R. (Ruffin) Green (1840-1869) (photograph of portrait), undated (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0009)
  - Portrait of Mr. and Mrs. Victor Bryant [Jr.?] (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0010)
  - Portraits of [George] Watts Carr, Jr. (1918-2006), circa 1936 (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0011)
    High school portraits? Two takes on one negative sheet. No print in collection.
  - Trinity Church, downtown Durham, before 1923 (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0012)
    Print is present in collection.
  - Hospital and Country Club trolley near car barn, E. Main St., before 1930 (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0013)
  - Old-style stoplight and pole with directional signs for cities, unknown intersection, circa 1920 (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0014)
  - Five Points Drug Company, 1920s (Box 1, Image RL-11373-N-0015)